<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>buglix.org</title><link>https://buglix.org/</link><description>Recent content on buglix.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 08:32:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://buglix.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QMK and KBD67 Lite R3 ISO</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/qmk-and-kbd67-iso/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 08:32:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/qmk-and-kbd67-iso/</guid><description>I recently decided I wanted to build my keyboard based on the KBDfans KBD67 Lite R3 ISO kit. With my two other keyboards, the Keychron Q1 and KBNordic Nordic60, I&amp;rsquo;ve built custom QMK firmware as I want some extra features that are not possible with VIA alone. Things like leader keys and having easily having keymaps and macros in sync across different keyboards. I also really like the Space Cadet feature, having the left and right shift keys act as left and right parenthesis if tapped and shift if held.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://buglix.org/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 21:11:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Obsidian Notes</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/2021-02-13-obsidian-notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 15:33:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/2021-02-13-obsidian-notes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying Obsidian and Roam Research a little now and then ever since they first came out. I recently stumbled across Nick Milo&amp;rsquo;s Linking Your Thinking Youtube channel and it got me excited about the idea of utilizing linking better in my note taking. I&amp;rsquo;ve now started in Obsidian and I even created a publish site at https://notes.buglix.org where I&amp;rsquo;ll publish some things soon.</description></item><item><title>iPad Mount for Volvo XC60</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/ipad-holder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 20:57:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/ipad-holder/</guid><description>The results of one weeks design, prototyping and prints - a modular iPad holder for neck rest mounting. Made an adapter that fits fairly new Volvo XC60s.</description></item><item><title>One Note to Rule Them All</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/one-note-to-rule-them-all/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 20:49:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/one-note-to-rule-them-all/</guid><description>Since Evernote changed their pricing and usage terms two weeks ago it seems people are desperately exporting all their notes and looking for alternatives. Reading tweets and articles on the topic it seems like Microsoft OneNote is the beacon of hope for many. It provides roughly the same feature set, it’s available on many devices and it is free to use. So far so good.
What makes me worried about OneNote though is that there is no way of exporting all of your notes, like you can with Evernote.</description></item><item><title>Ode to plain text</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/2014-09-03-ode-to-plain-text/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 15:33:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/2014-09-03-ode-to-plain-text/</guid><description>Since I first started using Getting Things Done back in 2006 I have constantly been on the lookout for the next cool method, system, setup or app. Everything from a fully analog system with notebooks and 43 physical folders to every standalone app or subscription model there is.
The problem I have and share with so many others is that I fiddle more with the setup and tools than I actually do using it to get productive.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Apps of 2009</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/my-favorite-apps-of-2009/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 20:47:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/my-favorite-apps-of-2009/</guid><description>The number of applications in Apple’s App Store has exploded during 2009 and it is getting harder and harder to find new stuff. Therefore I thought it was a good idea to share my favorite applications of 2009 (mostly based on the apps I have used the most).
Reeder
As a Google Reader addict I have tried several iPhone apps for accessing my feeds while on the road. First I used the mobile version of Google Reader, simply browsing to the site in Safari.</description></item><item><title>My Drobo Turned on Me</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/my-drobo-turned-on-me/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 20:43:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/my-drobo-turned-on-me/</guid><description>After I have been recommending Drobo to almost everyone I have talked to for roughly a month (bought it on recommendation from TWiT), it suddenly turned on me this weekend. It all started Saturday morning. I have been using the Drobo as a media backend for my Plex/Mac Mini HTPC setup. RipIthas helped me backup my DVD collection and I have carefully named each movie so that the IMDB scraper in Plex can find information about it.</description></item><item><title>Garmin Edge 705 and Open Street Map</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/garmin-edge-705-and-open-street-map/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 20:45:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/garmin-edge-705-and-open-street-map/</guid><description>I recently bought a Garmin Edge 705 bike computer to help with my training for next years Vätternrundan (a Swedish 300K bike race around the second largest lake). It was quite expensive in itself which led to a small chock when I saw the price of the maps – almost 50% of the price of the GPS unit.
I googled for free maps and after a while I stumbled upon openmtbmap.</description></item><item><title>Jaunty Jackalope on Asus Eee Pc 1008HA</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/jaunty-jackalope-on-asus-eee-pc-1008ha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 20:39:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/jaunty-jackalope-on-asus-eee-pc-1008ha/</guid><description>Two days ago, during a time of intensive writers block, I went out and bought an Asus 1008HA to use as a lightweight writing machine and surf station. Since I brought it home I have removed Windows XP and installed Ubuntu Jaynty Jackalope (both standard desktop edition and netbook remix) and Intel’s Moblin 2.0 without running into any serious trouble.
Neither the wired or the wireless network does not work out of the box (works as a charm in Moblin though) after installing, but it was just a matter of downloading the .</description></item><item><title>Taskpaper API for Python</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/taskpaper-api-for-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 20:37:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/taskpaper-api-for-python/</guid><description>Just created a Python API for reading and modifying (even if all the modify features are not complete yet) TaskPaper files. The (so far very small) project is hosted at my GitHub page here. The file you are looking for if you want to play with the API can be found here.</description></item><item><title>Lomo, Lomo, Lomo</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/lomo-lomo-lomo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 20:26:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/lomo-lomo-lomo/</guid><description>Take your camera everywhere you go Use it any time – day and night Lomography is not an inteference in your life, but part of it Try the shot from the hip Approach the objects of your lomographic desire as close as possible Don’t think Be fast You don’t have to know beforehand what you captured on film Afterwards either Don’t worry about any rules Lomographic Society International</description></item><item><title>As Simple as Possible, but not Simpler</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/as-simple-as-possible/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 20:28:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/as-simple-as-possible/</guid><description>A wise man once said that one should “Make everything as simple as possible, but not simpler“, something I have seen to be true in many areas of my life recently. I have been a practicioner of David Allen’s GTD method on and off for almost three years now. I have tried all kinds of implementations of the method, both in software and in paper based solutions like the Moleskine. I started with a lot of lists in a big text file, then a Moleskine setup (see PigPogPDA and Hacking a GTD Moleskine) then an array of different software solutions like TiddlyWiki, MonkeyGTD, ThinkingRock GTD, Midnigt Inbox, Todo.</description></item><item><title>10 Years of Digital Cameras</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/10-years-of-digital-cameras/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 20:31:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/10-years-of-digital-cameras/</guid><description>The ultimate camera?
I recently sold my Nikon D90 since I realized that I o/nly use an SLR-camera when I’m on vacation. In everyday situations it is just to heavy to throw in the backpack. While thinking about which camera to go with instead (an ongoing thought process of mine) it struck me that I have been a digital camera user for 10 years this year, and during this time frame bought and sold no less than 16 cameras (almost two per year).</description></item><item><title>Going Postal</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/going-postal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 20:34:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/going-postal/</guid><description>After your computer crashes for the second time of the day and you reboot, the last thing you want to be greeted with when starting the Mail.app is this:
This is not the first time Mail.app forgets who I am and where my e-mail is stored. Fortunately I solely use IMAP and thus all messages are safely stored and backed up on a server somewhere. Unfortunately, for Mail.app, this was the last time I go through the agonizing pain of setting it up the way I want just to have to redo it in a couple of weeks.</description></item><item><title>New Camera (Again)</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/new-camera-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 20:01:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/new-camera-again/</guid><description>After much research I finally settled for the Nikon D60. My main requirements where lightweight and DSLR (for image quality). The D60 seemed to fit my requirements best at this time, and I have wanted to try Nikon again (had an advanced compact 5-6 years ago). Now I’m just waiting for my Jimmy Bo to arrive so I will look smashing at the streets 🙂</description></item><item><title>My Daily Go Bag</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/my-daily-go-bag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 19:59:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/my-daily-go-bag/</guid><description>After re-organizing my messenger bag today I was inspired by Lifehacker article “Show us your go bag“, took a photo and documented everything inside. It helps me remember all the things I actually lug around each day so that when I need them I really use them. It have happened all to often that I have solved situations much to complicated just because I didn’t use the tools at hand (or in my bag).</description></item><item><title>Moleskine Delight</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/moleskine-delight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2008 19:57:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/moleskine-delight/</guid><description>On a business trip to Stockholm today I had some time to kill and went to the pen and paper section of the department store Åhlens to search for a new notebook (I admit, I have a notebook addiction). Naturally I first checked the Moleskine shelf as they produce the most convenient and good looking notebooks on the planet. To my surprise they had a new model with soft cover without the classic elastic rubber band.</description></item><item><title>A Week With the Straight Razor</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/a-week-with-the-straight-razor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 19:56:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/a-week-with-the-straight-razor/</guid><description>I have shaved with the straight razor for almost a week now and I must say that I’m pleased with the performance so far. It will take some time to get the same results that I’m used to with the safety razor, but it is kind of fun learning to master this lost form of art 🙂
I will keep the blog updated with more information as I progress. It is a material hobby, and I will try to review things as I use them (knifes, brushes, soaps, oils, after shaves etc).</description></item><item><title>A Very Usable MacOS X Key Combo</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/a-very-usable-os-x-key-combo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 19:55:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/a-very-usable-os-x-key-combo/</guid><description>Found a nice post at Lifehacker today which lists ten things you forgot that you mac can do, and to be frank, I didn’t even know it could do this.
Highlight any word by selecting it, or simply hover the mouse pointer over it and press Control + Command + D, and a stylish pop-up will appear with a definition of the word from the built in dictionary. Very nifty.</description></item><item><title>Evernote Mac 1.1</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/evernote-mac-1-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 19:53:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/evernote-mac-1-1/</guid><description>Uffe mentioned that TUAW (Evernote Mac 1.1 – The Unofficial Apple Weblog (TUAW)) is highlighting that version 1.1 of Evernote was released recently. I have used Evernote for a couple of weeks now and so far I think it has great potential, but still needs a lot of polishing. If you are interested in testing this innovative note taking concept, leave a comment and I will send you an invite (have 14 left right now).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Economics</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/open-source-economics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 19:52:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/open-source-economics/</guid><description>Yesterday I had my lunchin front of the computer at the office and since I’m easily bored by just sitting and eating by myself, I fired up Safari and browsed to TED.com for a little meal entertainment. While enjoying my Marinara Meatball sub I watched Yochai Benkler’s seminar Open-source economics, which was really interesting. He draws similar conclusions as Tor Nørretranders in his book The Generous Man – that we are moving towards a sharing community and how the mechanics of open source project organization (i.</description></item><item><title>I took the Straight Razor Plunge</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/i-took-the-straight-razor-plunge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2008 19:50:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/i-took-the-straight-razor-plunge/</guid><description>During almost a year I have shaved using a safety razor and it has given me a closer shave than all electric shavers or plastic Mach-X-style Gilette razors I have tried so far. It took some time to get the right technique, thus avoiding razor burn and pimples, but it was worth the wait. When you get a perfect shave it feels really smooth, and lasts longer than a shave performed with a traditional electric shaver.</description></item><item><title>Richard M. Stallman - Gothenburg 2007</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/richard-m-stallman---gothenburg-2007/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 19:48:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/richard-m-stallman---gothenburg-2007/</guid><description>Yesterday I attended Richard Stallman’s session titled “Free Software and Beyond: Human Rights in the Use of Software and Other Published Works” in Gothenborg.
I expected it to be two hours of Microsoft bashing (and it was too), but it turned out to be quite interesting. Even though I don’t agree with Stallman and FSF on all points and their arguments are not always “water proof”, I think it is necessary to have organizations like FSF/GNU to act as a counter weight to organizations like Microsoft and others.</description></item><item><title>GPS Frenzy</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/gps-frenzy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2007 19:47:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/gps-frenzy/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going for a hike in Abisko late this summer. As a gadget freak I just had to purchase a new gadget for this adventure – a Garmin eTrex Legend Cx. I have owned other GPS units before, but this one is so small, waterproof and straight forward to use (yeah I know it’s a sales pitch, but what the heck). What enticed me the most was not the possibility to see my position on a map at all times, but rather to have a very accurate trace of our hike afterwards.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu on Amilo Si 1520</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/ubuntu-on-amilo-si-1520/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 19:43:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/ubuntu-on-amilo-si-1520/</guid><description>If you are looking for a HOW TO on installation of Ubuntu, please scroll down a bit.
I recently bought a new laptop from Fujitsu-Siemens – the Amilo SI 1520. My requirements for this laptop was that it should be fairly cheap (max 1000 euros), run Linux with ease and feature a 12 inch wide screen.
After browsing through some local (Swedish) internet stores I soon concluded that I had to go with the high end consumer segment instead of the business segment, otherwise my budget requirement would have gone through the roof.</description></item><item><title>I'm on InterfaceLIFT!</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/im-on-interfacelift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2007 19:33:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/im-on-interfacelift/</guid><description>After an indoor macro shoot-out this weekend I decided to submit one of my more successful (at least to my liking) photos of a yellow rubber duck against a deep blue background to InterfaceLIFT (a popular place for things that prettifies ones desktop). In just 20 minutes I got the response that they liked my “Ducky” and even wanted more (my NES controller in purple).
I will now scan through my archive of photos for more desktop material and hope to have more photos featured at InterfaceLIFT.</description></item><item><title>Lightbox Revisited</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/lightbox-revisited/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2007 19:38:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/lightbox-revisited/</guid><description>I bought some new materials for my own home studio created by plastic tubes and some papers. Some of the shots actually turned out quite nicely like these peppers on a crisp yellow background. Go to my Flickr site for some more examples.
I will probably write a post later on about how I built the studio and how it looks.</description></item><item><title>Code Prettifier</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/code-prettifier/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 19:22:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/code-prettifier/</guid><description>I have now completed a web based syntax highlighter that can prettify any code that is already available on the net (like via WebCVS/SVN, or just plain uploaded files). It has support for Java, Python, C++ and Ruby among others. To use it, simply enter a URL to some code you want to be highlighted and decide if you want line numbers or not. You can also chose to only retrieve a link that you can use on your own homepage/blog/forum/whatever.</description></item><item><title>Cross Platform Tooling the Best of Two Worlds</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/cross-platform-tooling---the-best-of-two-worlds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 19:22:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/cross-platform-tooling---the-best-of-two-worlds/</guid><description>I have recently been working on a project where the target operating system is Windows XP. Since I do not have a Windows XP installation, I started writing code on Linux and since it worked fine in the beginning, I continued doing so throughout the development phase of the project. At a later stage when it was time to start testing and integrating on Windows I discovered one or two platform specific errors in the code, that I easily fixed.</description></item><item><title>Pretty code</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/pretty-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 19:08:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/pretty-code/</guid><description>Something I have wanted for a long time is an efficient way of highlighting syntax for an arbitrary file. Like uploading a file to some server and then execute a query like this:
http://myserver.com/scripts/highlight?url=http://www.someserver.com/MyClass.java&amp;amp;language=java&amp;amp;showlines=false
And it would generate a clean HTML-output with the code highlighted and pretty.
Since I have not found any site that allows me to do that (even if this one is close) I’m going to write my own service based on SilverCity.</description></item><item><title>Image Grinder Light</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/image-grinder-light/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2006 19:20:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/image-grinder-light/</guid><description>In my Projects page I have a description of a tool called Image Grinder wich I’m working on. Since I’m implementing it in C++ and wxWidgets it takes some time (I don’t think C++ is a very creative language – don’t know why I chose it realy). Today I switched mode of the camera to capture both Raw and JPEG’s for each photo, and when I was about to transfer the images to my PC I realized that I need a good “Image Grinder” to copy the images to their locations.</description></item><item><title>New Photos Uploaded to flickr</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/new-photos-uploaded-to-flickr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 19:14:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/new-photos-uploaded-to-flickr/</guid><description>During my vacation I have re-organized my digital photo collection. That includes starting to use digiKam to organize them, and flickr.com to show them.
My latest batch were taken during my first visit to the United States in February 2005. I was there to attend the yearly Eclipse conference Eclipsecon.</description></item><item><title>New Photos on Flickr</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/new-photos-on-flickr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2006 19:17:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/new-photos-on-flickr/</guid><description>I just uploaded a small batch of images from when I and a friend (Olle) visited Abisko in the northern parts of Sweden back in 2004. The early winter there caught us by surprise, so we had to cut the joureny short, but still managed to get some nice shots out of it.
I also added some of my abstract and nature photos. In good time I hope to add more or less all my photos to flickr since they do not have a storage limit (even if there is a traffic limit of 2GB per month).</description></item><item><title>New Project of Mine</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/new-project-of-mine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2006 19:19:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/new-project-of-mine/</guid><description>I have acquired the domain buglix.se where I soon will start a new web project. For four years now I have written articles for different paper magazines and now I think it is time to share these articles online too. The articles will be in Swedish only, and I will publish them when I get time to it (which will be soon since I’m on vacation ).
First article I just now published my first article on buglix.</description></item><item><title>Gaim Plugin Development (in Ubuntu)</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/gaim-plugin-development-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 19:12:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/gaim-plugin-development-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>I recently remembered that Gaim has a nice Perl API for writing plugins (or actually I was rembembered by a friend). I decided to test it out by writing a plugin for displaying the current playing song in Rhythmbox in instant messages when the keyword ‘%rb’ is found (I know there is a plugin for that already, but I did not get that to work).
The first step was to download the small source for the Perl API example from the Gaim site and try to get it to work.</description></item><item><title>BinOcular - Bits in Structure</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/binocular-bits-in-structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 19:08:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/binocular-bits-in-structure/</guid><description>I would like to take the oppertunity to talk a little about our latest project at Purple Scout.
BinOcular - Tabs featureBinOcular is the response to an ever-growing need to browse different kinds of binary files, both modern well documented formats, as well as obscure legacy ones. When developing products, the developer is frequently faced with the problem to deal with binary files in some way or the other. The reasons for having to deal with binary data formats today are many, and could for example be viewing of scientific data files, looking into image formats for specific headers, “debugging” of the output from some tool or simply having to deal with legacy data formats.</description></item><item><title>Minor Eclipse Util Plugin</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/minor-eclipse-util-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2006 19:07:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/minor-eclipse-util-plugin/</guid><description>I have discovered that during development in Eclipse, you sometimes have to restart the workbench for various reasons. The “File-&amp;gt;Switch workspace” feature is ok for that I guess, but sometimes when you are working with several different workspaces, the value in the switch workspace dialog is not in sync with what you are currently using – which will cause some unecessary delay.
Since it is so little effort needed creating something that just restarts from the current workspace, I decided to create a plug-in for it and publish it for anyone who feel the need to be able to restart Eclipse swiftly.</description></item><item><title>Portage Update Checker</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/portage-update-checker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 19:03:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/portage-update-checker/</guid><description>Here is a little script I once wrote to check if new updates exists in the Portage Tree (Gentoo). If so, it sends an e-mail to the owner of the script. Run it as a cron job and don’t forget to change user_address and smtpserver.
#!/usr/bin/python # Copyright Emil Erlandsson 2005 import os,smtplib user_address = &amp;#34;receivers address&amp;#34; smtpserver = &amp;#34;some_smtp_server&amp;#34; if os.spawnvp(os.P_WAIT, &amp;#34;emerge&amp;#34;, [&amp;#34;emerge&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sync&amp;#34;]) == 0: pipe = os.</description></item><item><title>Python Hacking Revisited</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/python-hacking-revisited/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 19:00:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/python-hacking-revisited/</guid><description>It is about a year since I last layed hands on Python, but recently my interest started to grow again. As a former Perl-hacker, I must say I really like Python in a lot of way. It has the same power as Perl, but with better structure and more readable syntax.
Anyway… While coding some utility scripts on my Windows machine I found a need for searching the PATH environment variable after some executables.</description></item><item><title>Iwftools Created on SourceForge</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/iwftools-created-on-sourceforge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 18:58:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/iwftools-created-on-sourceforge/</guid><description>A little hobby scripting of mine resulted in the creation of a new Open Source project at SourceForge.net. At the moment I’m working on the libraries so I can publish them in a week or two. If you think it sounds interesting you should check it later for new versions.
http://sourceforge.net/projects/iwftools/</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Find the Bug</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/2005-05-22-book-review-find-the-bug/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2005 18:45:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/2005-05-22-book-review-find-the-bug/</guid><description>Published 2005 by Addison Wesley and written by Adam Barr, this piece of work comes right from the press. It challenges the reader to analyse the source a step further like a “human debugger”. Many bugs are hidden during normal debugging and does not show up in unit tests.
To find these bugs, the programmer must actively read and understand what the code does (especially if the code is written by someone else).</description></item><item><title>Next Generation</title><link>https://buglix.org/posts/old/2005-05-21-next-generation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2005 17:56:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://buglix.org/posts/old/2005-05-21-next-generation/</guid><description>You are now reading my new blog. This time I will focus a little harder on software engineering and programming compared to my previous blogging attempts. Since this page is quite empty at the moment – spend some time at the linked sites to the right.</description></item></channel></rss>