<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>buglix.org</title>
 <link href="http://buglix.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://buglix.org/"/>
 <updated>2014-09-03T20:31:48+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://buglix.org</id>
 <author>
   <name>Emil Erlandsson</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Ode to plain text</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2014/09/03/ode-to-plain-text/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2014/09/03/ode-to-plain-text</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I first started using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done&quot;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; back in 2006 I have constantly been on the lookout for the next cool method, system, setup or app. Everything from a fully analog system with notebooks and 43 physical folders to every standalone app or subscription model there is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem I have and share with so many others is that I fiddle more with the setup and tools than I actually do using it to get productive. I really like the idea of fully fledged tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus&quot;&gt;Omnifocus&lt;/a&gt;, but after I get all my stuff in there I start to loose the overview perspective and after a few weeks I almost don&amp;#39;t want to open the app anymore. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found a pattern in the tools that I use - the more low-tech they are, the longer I stay with them. It&amp;#39;s something special about the freedom of just jotting something down in a notebook or being able to move text around freely on the screen. Paper based notebooks have the disadvantage that it&amp;#39;s hard to search and index them and that&amp;#39;s why I&amp;#39;ve eventually left them behind. I still take most of my notes with pen and paper, but I like my task management digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Enter TaskPaper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hogbaysoftware.com/static/taskpaper/mac_os_screen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;taskpaper&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I have started to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hogbaysoftware.com/products/taskpaper&quot;&gt;TaskPaper&lt;/a&gt;, by Hogbay Software. Or actually, re-started as I have tried it in the passed and dismissed it as it doesn&amp;#39;t have all the bells and whistles of something like OmniFocus. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not only an app, but also a way to structure tasks, projects, tags and notes in plain text so it can be used with other plain text editors as well (more on that in a coming post). Hogbay&amp;#39;s website is not selling the concept very well, but there are two comprehensive articles by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/macdrifter&quot;&gt;Gabe Weatherhead&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macdrifter.com/2014/01/deconstructing-my-omnifocus-dependency.html&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macdrifter.com/2014/02/the-taskpaper-rd-notebook.html&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I use it the more I like it. There is some form of app for every platform I use. I can sync my TaskPaper document with Dropbox and use a variety of scripts and tools to manipulate them. It doesn&amp;#39;t provide me with a ton of settings I can fiddle with (which is good), but it let&amp;#39;s me create my own theme. As I really like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://color.smyck.org/&quot;&gt;SMYCK&lt;/a&gt; color scheme, I used it as a base for my theme as you can see below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emilerl/smyck-taskpaper/blob/master/Smyck.taskpapertheme&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/emilerl/smyck-taskpaper/master/smyck.png&quot; alt=&quot;smycktheme&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My favorite iPhone apps of 2009</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2010/01/08/my-favorite-iphone-apps-of-2009/"/>
   <updated>2010-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2010/01/08/my-favorite-iphone-apps-of-2009</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The number of applications in Apple&amp;#39;s App Store has exploded during 2009 and it is getting harder and harder to find new stuff. Therefore I thought it was a good idea to share my favorite applications of 2009 (mostly based on the apps I have used the most).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://erlandsson.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/photo-full.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://erlandsson.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/photo-thumb4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reederapp.com/&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As a &lt;a href=&quot;http://reader.google.com&quot;&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt; addict I have tried several iPhone apps for accessing my feeds while on the road. First I used the mobile version of Google Reader, simply browsing to the site in Safari. It didn&amp;#39;t map to the way I use reader though and later I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phantomfish.com/byline.html&quot;&gt;Byline&lt;/a&gt; (native app) which was a step in the right direction. After that I started using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsgator.com/Individuals/NetNewsWireiPhone/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;NetNewsWire&lt;/a&gt; which also improved the reading experience. It wasn&amp;#39;t until I found Reeder that I can say I&amp;#39;m happy with the reading experience on the iPhone. There are only a few features that I miss (such as reading items shared by others, or recommended items). One of the apps I use most days except Mail and Phone.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instapaper.com/iphone&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Instapaper is a good complement to Google Reader and other news services allowing me to read some of the longer articles when I have the time. Besides my Sony Reader Touch (via Calibre), the iPhone app is the place were I read most of the content from Instapaper.com.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atebits.com/tweetie-iphone/&quot;&gt;Tweetie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My Twitter usage goes up and down, but when I&amp;#39;m in the mood, I use Tweetie on the iPhone.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boxcar.io/&quot;&gt;Boxcar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A good complement to Tweetie, allowing me to get notifications about direct messages or mentions.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hipstamaticapp.com/&quot;&gt;Hipstamatic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Of all the camera apps I have tried, this is the only one I have kept. The various lenses and films you can buy in the application makes you want to experiment and try new things. For some examples, check &lt;a href=&quot;http://emilerl.posterous.com/paper-stuff&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Paper Stuff&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; at my Posterous blog.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=316377359&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Ninjawords&lt;/a&gt; [iTunes direct link]&lt;br&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2009/08/ninjawords&quot;&gt;controversy&lt;/a&gt; (via: Daring Fireball) around Ninjawords was actually the thing that got me to try it. As the web service (&lt;a href=&quot;http://ninjawords.com&quot;&gt;ninjawords.com&lt;/a&gt;) it is a really fast way of looking up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wiktionary.org/&quot;&gt;Wiktionary&lt;/a&gt; words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hoofien.com/Snatch/index.html&quot;&gt;Snatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In the summer of 09 I bought a Mac Mini and installed Plex. I didn&amp;#39;t want a complete keyboad and mouse setup, so instead I researched remote control solutions allowing me to remote control the Mini via my iPhone and WiFi (or BlueTooth). Even though it is a bit unstable from time to time, it is still my favorite way of controlling the Mini from the phone.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripit.com/uhp/iphone&quot;&gt;The TripIt App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Since I travel quite a lot, the TripIt app have saved me many times during sprints at airport trying to find out when the connecting flight departs.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.futureacoustic.com/soundcurtain/&quot;&gt;Soundcurtain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
While traveling it can be hard to find solitude and privacy to get some work done. Soundcurtain is a great cure, analyzing the environment sound volume via the mic and generates a sound to tune it out. I mostly use the rain mode.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipod/nike/&quot;&gt;Nike + iPod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Even though this is a built-in application I thought it was worth mentioning. If you have the Nike+ equipment it is a very nice way of keeping track of your exercise.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drinksapp.com/&quot;&gt;Top shelf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Previously named &amp;quot;Drinks&amp;quot;, Top shelf is my first stop for finding drink recipes and inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamieoliver.com/20-minute-meals/&quot;&gt;20 minute meals - Jamie Oliver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Another great stop for recipes. Nice inspiring photos and very clear instructions. I particularly like the shopping list feature. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=342699962&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Rat on a scooter XL&lt;/a&gt; [iTunes direct link]&lt;br&gt;
Most addictive game of 2009. I have a high score of 140 and it starts to get hard beating it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=307727765&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;DoodleJump&lt;/a&gt; [iTunes direct link]&lt;br&gt;
Second most addictive game of 2009. It does not have the same feeling of speed as Rat on a scooter, but it is still a good game. My highscore is 20.000-something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/se/app/sydsvenskan/id294010168?mt=8&quot;&gt;Sydsvenskan&lt;/a&gt; [iTunes direct link]&lt;br&gt;
My local newspaper. The app feels solid and always brings me the latest news. One of the better news outlets in Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/se/app/mobilblogg/id347854404?mt=8&quot;&gt;MobilBlogg&lt;/a&gt; [iTunes direct link]&lt;br&gt;
A friend and a colleague at &lt;a href=&quot;http://purplescout.se&quot;&gt;Purple Scout&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tobi.nu/&quot;&gt;Tobias/tru&lt;/a&gt; have created a very nice client for the Swedish micro blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://mobilblogg.nu&quot;&gt;mobilblogg.nu&lt;/a&gt; (requires account). Even though I don&amp;#39;t use mobilblogg.nu that much, I thought it was worth mentioning since it is a very nice and solid application. It is released as &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensource.purplescout.se/projects/show/mbiphone&quot;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stardefense.ngmoco.com/&quot;&gt;StarDefence&lt;/a&gt;
Before this game I wasn&amp;#39;t that much into tower defense games, but it has all changed now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firemint.com/flightcontrol/&quot;&gt;FlightControl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Addicive fun, especially to play against another player via BlueTooth.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lomo Lomo Lomo</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2009/05/27/lomo-lomo-lomo/"/>
   <updated>2009-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2009/05/27/lomo-lomo-lomo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take your camera everywhere you go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use it any time - day and night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lomography is not an inteference in your life, but part of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try the shot from the hip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approach the objects of your lomographic desire as close as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t think&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to know beforehand what you captured on film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Afterwards either&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t worry about any rules&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lomography.com/about/the-ten-golden-rules&quot;&gt;Lomographic Society International&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>10 years of digital cameras</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2009/05/24/10-years-of-digital-cameras/"/>
   <updated>2009-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2009/05/24/10-years-of-digital-cameras</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://microsites.lomography.com/diana/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://erlandsson.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/diana-camera.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Diana+, the ultimate camera?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently sold my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Nikon/nikon_d90.asp&quot;&gt;Nikon D90&lt;/a&gt; since I realized that I only use an SLR-camera when I&amp;#39;m on vacation. In everyday situations it is just to heavy to throw in the backpack. While thinking about which camera to go with instead (an ongoing thought process of mine) it struck me that I have been a digital camera user for 10 years this year, and during this time frame bought and sold no less than 16 cameras (almost two per year). I have owned everything from the most simple VGA-resolution cameras like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Agfa/agfa_cl18.asp&quot;&gt;Agfa ePhoto CL18&lt;/a&gt; to professional models like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_eos40d.asp&quot;&gt;Canon EOS 40D&lt;/a&gt; with all kinds of accessories and tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realization of changing camera almost twice a year got me thinking if I&amp;#39;m only in digital cameras for the chase of the next new model or why I take photos at all. My interest in photography started way back in the beginning of the nineties when I got to borrow my fathers analog &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.photoethnography.com/ClassicCameras/index-frameset.html?AsahiPentaxSpotmaticSPII.html%7EmainFrame&quot;&gt;Ashia Pentax Spotmatic SPI&lt;/a&gt;I, which I still think is a very good camera. Before that I used a compact camera only for vacation and pet (our late cat Findus) snaps. When I got my hands on the Pentax and the fine lenses that came with it, I realized that photography wasn&amp;#39;t only a way of freezing a moment, it was a creative outlet as well. I started shooting more artistic and especially nature/landscape shots. It was always a thrill to get the film back from the camera shop and looking through the master pieces. The years went by and my interest in photography faded until almost 10 years later when my upper secondary school got a digital camera (the revolution!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.photoethnography.com/ClassicCameras/index-frameset.html?AsahiPentaxSpotmaticSPII.html%7EmainFrame&quot;&gt;Kodak DC200&lt;/a&gt;, a brick that produced grainy 640 by 480 pixel shots in bright light. Anything else than perfect shooting conditions and all you got was a pixel blur. That did not stop me for a second though. Even if the camera was school property, we were allowed to borrow it during evenings and weekends - a benefit I often took advantage of. Compared to shooting with the Pentax, this was like going back to my first compact, more of a memory freeze than an artistic outlet, but it was amazing to skip the whole development process and not having to pay for each shot. A year later I bought my first digital camera, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Agfa/agfa_cl18.asp&quot;&gt;Agfa ePhoto CL18&lt;/a&gt;, more ore less the same kind of camera as the DC200, but I didn&amp;#39;t have to ask someone every time I wanted to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pattern I have observed while going through my list of previously owned cameras is that I&amp;#39;m torn between artistic expression and my love for advanced technology. All my friends know that I&amp;#39;m a technology loving, early adopting gearhead who is always on the hunt for the next cool gadget. During the last 10 years there have been a small revolution in digital cameras which have fuled my fire for technology by releasing new and more advanced models each year. I love to read reviews of new cameras, dig in user forums (like dpreview.com), look at 200% enlargements of ISO comparisons between different camera models and so on. Of course that has been very good for the gadgetist in me, but not always a great match for the artistic photographer. I say &amp;quot;not always&amp;quot; because some of the cameras have unleashed the same kind of creative freedom I first experienced with the Spotmatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a couple of weeks I&amp;#39;m going on a trip to Japan and of course I want to take a lot of vacation snaps and also artistic images. With the realization that I&amp;#39;m often torn between creativity and technology (heart and brain?) I&amp;#39;m now hunting for a camera that I know will satisfy my artistic and creative side foremost. Right now I have a few contenders, but haven&amp;#39;t been able to decide yet. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/news/0902/09022401olympuse620.asp&quot;&gt;Olympus E-620&lt;/a&gt; seems to be a good compromise. It is an SLR, but it is very small and lightweight, especially if equipped with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cameralabs.com/reviews/Olympus_Zuiko_Digital_25mm_pancake/&quot;&gt;Zuiko 25mm pancake lens&lt;/a&gt;. My main arguments for the E-620 is that it has a swiveling screen and built-in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.olympusamerica.com/cpg_section/product.asp?product=1452&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Art Filters&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; (I know, it is just digital filters that is also easy to apply in post processing, but that&amp;#39;s thinking with the brain, not with the heart). Olympus will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/news/0809/08092208olympus_micro_four_thirds.asp&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt; another interesting camera in mid June as well. It is a micro four thirds camera in retro range finder style, something that sounds appealing to me. Another very interesting thing is something I saw on my last trip to Tokyo. It was a digital version of the Lomo camera &lt;a href=&quot;http://microsites.lomography.com/diana/&quot;&gt;Diana+&lt;/a&gt; (see pic above). I have always been drawn to Lomo cameras, but I don&amp;#39;t want to hassle with analog film anymore. A digital version would be very nice. Will check it again on my next visit in June (think I saw it at the department store &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tokyu-hands.co.jp/&quot;&gt;Tokyo Hands&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/news/0902/09022401olympuse620.asp&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://erlandsson.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/olympus-e-620_1.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Olympus E-620&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way I will soon be buying a new camera. The difference this time is that I will buy with my heart instead of my brain and hopefully snap a bunch of creative images on my next trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to take a look at my photos, either go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/emilerl&quot;&gt;my flickr page&lt;/a&gt; or&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fotosidan.se/member/view.htm?ID=3932&quot;&gt; my page at Fotosidan.se&lt;/a&gt; (a Swedish photography site). Of course I can give advice on the cameras I have previously owned if you are thinking of buying one, just send an e-mail (check the About page for info).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;My camera history&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1999 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Kodak/kodak_dc200.asp&quot;&gt;Kodak DC200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2000 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Agfa/agfa_cl18.asp&quot;&gt;Agfa ePhoto CL18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2001 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/FujiFilm/fuji_finepix1300.asp&quot;&gt;FujiFilm Finepix 1300&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2001 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Olympus/oly_c2100uz.asp&quot;&gt;Olympus C-2100 UZ (aka UZI)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2002 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/FujiFilm/fuji_finepix6900z.asp&quot;&gt;FujiFilm FinePix 6900 Zoom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2003 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/minoltadimagea1/&quot;&gt;Minolta Dimage A1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2004 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_eos300d.asp&quot;&gt;Canon EOS 300D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2005 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_eos20d.asp&quot;&gt;Canon EOS 20D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2006 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_sd630.asp&quot;&gt;Canon Digital Ixus 65&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2007 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_eos400d.asp&quot;&gt;Canon EOS 400D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2007 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_eos40d.asp&quot;&gt;Canon EOS 40D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2008 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Canon/canon_g9.asp&quot;&gt;Canon Powershot G9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2008 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Sigma/sigma_dp1.asp&quot;&gt;Sigma DP1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2008 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Nikon/nikon_d60.asp&quot;&gt;Nikon D60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2008 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Panasonic/panasonic_dmclx3.asp&quot;&gt;Panasonic Lumix LX3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2009 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/specs/Nikon/nikon_d90.asp&quot;&gt;Nikon D90&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Moleskine delight!</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2008/05/21/moleskine-delight/"/>
   <updated>2008-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2008/05/21/moleskine-delight</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On a business trip to Stockholm today I had some time to kill and went to the pen and paper section of the department store &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ahlens.se&quot;&gt;Åhlens&lt;/a&gt; to search for a new notebook (I admit, I have a notebook addiction). Naturally I first checked the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moleskine.com&quot;&gt;Moleskine&lt;/a&gt; shelf as they produce the most convenient and good looking notebooks on the planet. To my surprise they had a new model with soft cover without the classic elastic rubber band. It was available in five different colors which is new to me .. have never seen anything but black Moleskines. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I bought one and when I got home the converter and Black/Blue ink for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lamy.com/eng/b2c/AL-star/025&quot;&gt;Lamy Al-Star&lt;/a&gt; had arrived with the mail... time for some serious writing action ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://erlandsson.files.wordpress.com/2008/05/529091_64006668.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://erlandsson.files.wordpress.com/2008/05/529091_64006668.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Notebooks&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Open Source Economics</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2008/05/14/open-source-economics/"/>
   <updated>2008-05-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2008/05/14/open-source-economics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I had my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subway.com/applications/menu/images/400_x/meatball-01.jpg&quot;&gt;lunch&lt;/a&gt; in front of the computer at the office and since I&amp;#39;m easily bored by just sitting and eating by myself, I fired up Safari and browsed to TED.com for a little meal entertainment. While enjoying my Marinara Meatball sub I watched Yochai Benkler&amp;#39;s seminar &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/view/id/247&quot;&gt;Open-source economics&lt;/a&gt;, which was really interesting. He draws similar conclusions as Tor Nørretranders in his book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1560257288/qid=1149782680/sr=1-1/ref=sr_1_1/103-0163772-4243843?s=books&amp;amp;v=glance&amp;amp;n=283155/&quot;&gt;The Generous Man&lt;/a&gt; - that we are moving towards a sharing community and how the mechanics of open source project organization (i.e. a lot of people sharing for a greater good) is widely used by large organizations such as NASA. Very interesting video indeed. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A very usable OS X key combo</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2008/05/14/a-very-usable-os-x-key-combo/"/>
   <updated>2008-05-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2008/05/14/a-very-usable-os-x-key-combo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://erlandsson.files.wordpress.com/2008/05/autodict.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://erlandsson.files.wordpress.com/2008/05/autodict.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dictionary pop up&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Found a nice post at Lifehacker today which lists &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/390226/top-10-things-you-forgot-your-mac-can-do&quot;&gt;ten things you forgot that you mac can do&lt;/a&gt;, and to be frank, I didn&amp;#39;t even know it could do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlight any word by selecting it, or simply hover the mouse pointer over it and press &lt;strong&gt;Control + Command + D&lt;/strong&gt;, and a stylish pop-up will appear with a definition of the word from the built in dictionary. Very nifty.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I took the straight razor plunge</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2008/05/13/i-took-the-straight-razor-plunge/"/>
   <updated>2008-05-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2008/05/13/i-took-the-straight-razor-plunge</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During almost a year I have shaved using a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Safety_razor&quot;&gt;safety razor&lt;/a&gt; and it has given me a closer shave than all electric shavers or plastic Mach-X-style Gilette razors I have tried so far. It took some time to get the right technique, thus avoiding razor burn and pimples, but it was worth the wait. When you get a perfect shave it feels really smooth, and lasts longer than a shave performed with a traditional electric shaver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I&amp;#39;m happy with the performance of my safety razor, I wanted something more - an even smoother shave. When I first bought the safety razor I found cut throat razors (or straight razor/open razor) in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gents.se&quot;&gt;web shop&lt;/a&gt; and started researching this lost art form on the web. The precision and danger (it is not that dangerous, but still, they don&amp;#39;t call it &amp;quot;razor sharp&amp;quot; for nothing) intrigued me, and I wanted to see if it was possible to get an even smoother shave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time of hesitation, I finally bought an &lt;strong&gt;Edwin Jagger Cut Throat&lt;/strong&gt; razor and a &lt;strong&gt;Dovo strap&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gents.se&quot;&gt;Gents.se&lt;/a&gt;. When I came home I whipped up some soap and covered the back side of my hand for a test run. It was kind of a strange feeling running this super sharp thing just millimeter(s) over the veins in the hand. It went well, but I was not ready to use it on my face just yet so I watched a lot of YouTube shaving videos last night... here is a small collection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jvu1F4f7bdQ&quot;&gt;A shave with a straight razor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JUK56EqF-B0&quot;&gt;How to shave with a straight razor part 1 - equipment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iLbpe62bubk&quot;&gt;How to shave with a straight razor part 2 - The Shave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aI4ak1lJgY4&quot;&gt;Straight razor shave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also read a long and interesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shavemyface.com/downloads/The-Straight-Razor-Shave.pdf&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) about it and finally felt that I was ready for a serious test run. So this morning I locked the bathroom door (to avoid any unnecessary stress like sudden interruptions :-) ) and started my first cut throat shave. It took some time to get a steady hand, but after a couple of strokes I thought it went pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I didn&amp;#39;t cut myself, I still have a long road before I get the same results as with the safety razor and I guess even more time to reach the nirvana of shaving, but at the same time as it is a daily habit it is also kind of a small hobby. During the shave it is almost impossible to think about other things which gives the whole process something of a zen feeling to it. Usually I just rush through my morning routine, so this can be something to build it around - a calm start of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Richard M. Stallman, Gothenborg 2007</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2007/05/17/richard-m-stallman-gothenborg-2007/"/>
   <updated>2007-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2007/05/17/richard-m-stallman-gothenborg-2007</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/emilerl/502386938/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/232/502386938_8fbde7f970_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended Richard Stallman&amp;#39;s session titled &amp;quot;Free Software and Beyond: Human Rights in the Use of Software and Other Published Works&amp;quot; in Gothenborg.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected it to be two hours of Microsoft bashing (and it was too), but it turned out to be quite interesting. Even though I don&amp;#39;t agree with Stallman and FSF on all points and their arguments are not always &amp;quot;water proof&amp;quot;, I think it is necessary to have organizations like FSF/GNU to act as a counter weight to organizations like Microsoft and others.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ubuntu on Amilo SI 1520</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2007/02/20/ubuntu-on-amilo-si-1520/"/>
   <updated>2007-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2007/02/20/ubuntu-on-amilo-si-1520</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/emilerl/396526427/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/166/396526427_7c5efdb471_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
  If you are  looking for a HOW TO on installation of Ubuntu, please scroll down a bit.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently bought a new laptop from Fujitsu-Siemens - the Amilo SI 1520. My requirements for this laptop was that it should be fairly cheap (max 1000 euros), run Linux with ease and feature a 12 inch wide screen.
After browsing through some local (Swedish) internet stores I soon concluded that I had to go with the high end consumer segment instead of the business segment, otherwise my budget requirement would have gone through the roof. I narrowed the selection down to either the Lenovo 3000 V100 or the FSC Amilo SI 1520. The Lenovo sported a higher build quality, but the FSC had better specs in almost any area (CPU, HDD, battery time etc). Both of them were proven to run Linux (Ubuntu and Gentoo), but the resources on the web was very limited (that is one of the reasons for me writing this article right now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing Ubuntu 6.10 on this piece of hardware was very straightforward. I just chose to resize my Windows XP partition (want to keep it for some experimentation) to 10 GB and use the rest for Ubuntu.
After the installation was completed it was just a matter of installing the 915resolution package to get the native resolution (1280 x 800) of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wireless network card (Intel Corporation PRO/Wireless 3945ABG, kernel module ipw3945) was detected without problems, but ipw3945 and Gnome Network Manager applet 0.6.3 did not play together. It didn&amp;#39;t take long until I found out that 0.6.4 supports ipw3945 and is available in the development version of Ubuntu (Feisty 7.04).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it could be fun to test the latest Ubuntu (and have nice wireless controls in Gnome) so I started to upgrade my Edge to Feisty. It is a very simple procedure. Simply make sure that your system is up to date. Then run the command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;gksudo &amp;quot;update-manager -c -d&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it whines about authorization problems you must execute GPG as the super user (root) one time before running the update-manager. It is also very simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo su
gpg
[CTRL+c]
exit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then run the update-manager again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Hardware status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read a few articles about Linux on the Amilo SI 1520 and the only thing that seems a bit tricky is the built-in microphone. I can confirm that it does not work out of the box, but I have not tried to get it working. Other than that all works fine, even the so called multimedia-buttons and suspend/hibernate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tuxmobil.org/fujitsu.html&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://tuxmobil.org/pics/tuxmobil_sticker.png&quot; alt=&quot;TuxMobil - Linux on Laptops, Notebooks, PDAs and Mobile Phones&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I'm on InterfaceLIFT!</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2007/01/21/im-on-interfacelift/"/>
   <updated>2007-01-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2007/01/21/im-on-interfacelift</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/emilerl/sets/72157594489085394/&quot;&gt;indoor macro shoot-out&lt;/a&gt; this weekend I decided to submit one of my more successful (at least to my liking) photos of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/emilerl/363875988/in/set-72157594489085394/&quot;&gt;yellow rubber duck against a deep blue background&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.interfacelift.com&quot;&gt;InterfaceLIFT&lt;/a&gt; (a popular place for things that prettifies ones desktop). In just 20 minutes I got the response that they liked my &amp;quot;Ducky&amp;quot; and even wanted more (my NES controller in purple).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will now scan through my archive of photos for more desktop material and hope to have more photos featured at InterfaceLIFT.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cross platform tooling - the best of two worlds</title>
   <link href="http://buglix.org/2006/12/31/cross-platform-tooling-the-best-of-two-worlds/"/>
   <updated>2006-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://buglix.org/2006/12/31/cross-platform-tooling-the-best-of-two-worlds</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have recently been working on a project where the target operating system is Windows XP. Since I do not have a Windows XP installation, I started writing code on Linux and since it worked fine in the beginning, I continued doing so throughout the development phase of the project. At a later stage when it was time to start testing and integrating on Windows I discovered one or two platform specific errors in the code, that I easily fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major benefit was that I could use free tools for validating the software, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://valgrind.org/&quot;&gt;Valgrind&lt;/a&gt; (with CallGrind enabled for profiling data), &lt;a href=&quot;http://kcachegrind.sourceforge.net/cgi-bin/show.cgi&quot;&gt;KCacheGrind&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/binutils/manual/gprof-2.9.1/gprof.html&quot;&gt;GProf&lt;/a&gt; that would have been hard, or even impossible in some situation if I had developed only on Windows XP.
Just for the fun of it, I tried to build it on Mac OS X 10.4 just to see if it worked - and it did! Right out of the box. That is another major benefit of multi platform development. The chances that it works right out of the box on a new platform is significantly higher than if only one target platform is used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I now could build the code on three platforms without breaking a sweat, I added multiple targets to our &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.purplescout.se/2006/12/29/automatic-multiplatform-build-and-test-system/&quot;&gt;automatic build&lt;/a&gt; system. That was simply to prevent that new code that would prevent the multi platform build qualities should be introduced into the system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
